Serge Diaghilev/Serge Lifar Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- I. Printed Music Material, 1750-1950 (Box 1-67)
  - A. General (Box 1-65)
    - Glinka, Mikhaĭl
      - Proshchanie s Peterburgom See: L'alouette, Box 24, Folder 8 See: Zhavoronok, Box 25, Folder 23 See: Poputnaia piesnia, Box 25, Folder 5
      - Ruslan i Liudmila See: Audran, Edmond
      - Sobranie muzykal'nykh pies See: Box 66, Folder 9
      - Souvenir d'une nuit d'été à Madrid. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d., Arranged by M. Balakirev for piano, four hands; score; 21 p.; Plate no. 4435. (Box-folder 25/10)
      - Tarantelle. St. Petersburg: M. Bernard, n.d., Solo piano; score; 2 p.; Plate no. N.11.A.No.12. (Box-folder 25/11)
      - Thema con variationi Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 3256. (Box-folder 25/12)
      - Thème de l'opéra Faniska de Cherubini See: Sobranie muzykal'nykh pies, Box 66, Folder 9
      - Thème de Mozart. [=Variations on a theme of Mozart.] Moscow: P. IUrgenson, n.d. See also: Variations sur un thème de Mozart, Box 25, Folder 21, Solo piano or harp; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 3222 (3221). (Box-folder 25/13)
      - Toska. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, 1878., Voice (T) and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 3229.; Language note: Russian (Box-folder 25/14)
      - Trot de cavalerie, no. 1. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 2 p.; Plate no. 3226. (Box-folder 25/15)
      - Trot de cavalerie, no. 2. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 3226. (Box-folder 25/16)
      - Tu sei figlia e lodo. Moscow: P. IUrgenson, 1878., Voice (S) and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 3244.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 25/17)
      - Val's-Fantaziia. Moscow: A. Gutkheĭl', n.d., Arranged by B. Engelhardt for piano, four hands; 19 p.; Plate no. 2278. (Box-folder 25/18)
      - Valse See: Sobranie muzykal'nykh pies, Box 66, Folder 9
      - Valse favorite [B-flat major]. St. Petersburg: F. Stellovskiĭ, n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. 876. (Box-folder 25/19)
      - Valse mélodique [E-flat major]. St. Petersburg: F. Stellovskiĭ, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 873. (Box-folder 25/20)
      - Variations sur un thème de Mozart. Moscow: P. Jurgenson, n.d. See also: Thème de Mozart, Box 25, Folder 13, Solo piano or harp; score; 9 p.; Plate no. 3221 (3222). (Box-folder 25/21)
      - La vie pour le Tsar. [=A Life for the Tsar.] Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 435 p.; Plate no. 3031.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French; Language note: German (Box-folder 25/22)
      - Zhavoronok. [Proshchanie s Peterburgom, no. 10; =L'alouette.] Moscow: Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo, Muzykal'nyĭ sektor, 1923. See also: L'alouett, Box 24, Folder 8, Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 30242.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 25/23)
    - Gluck, Christoph Willibald
      - Orphée. Braunschweig: H. Litolff, n.d., Arranged by L. Köhler for solo piano; score; 60 p.; Plate no. 3768 (Box-folder 25/24)
      - Orpheus. Leipzig: C.F. Peters, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 142 p.; Plate no. 9902.; Language note: German; Language note: French (Box-folder 25/25)
    - Godard, Benjamin
      - Air de ballet. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.5093.No.1. (Box-folder 26/1)
      - Aubade, op. 133. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Violin and piano; violin part, piano score; 5 p.; 11 p.; Plate no. J.4572.H. (Box-folder 26/2)
      - Berceuse d'enfant. Paris: A. Choudens, 1896., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.10172.; Language note: French (Box-folder 26/3)
      - Bohémienne, op. 40. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 6 p.; Plate no. D. & F.2469. (Box-folder 26/4)
      - Brésilienne, op. 51. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.3584. (Box-folder 26/5)
      - Carillon. [Paris]: [L. Grus], n.d., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. L.G.5093.No.2.; incomplete after p. 4 (Box-folder 26/6)
      - Les champs. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. L.G.4604. (Box-folder 26/7)
      - Chemin faisant: En courant, op. 53, no. 1. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. L.G.3441.(No.1). (Box-folder 26/8)
      - Chemin faisant: En pleurant, op. 53, no. 2. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.3441.(No.2). (Box-folder 26/9)
      - Chemin faisant: En chantant, op. 53, no. 3. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.3441.(No.3). (Box-folder 26/10)
      - Chemin faisant: En riant, op. 53, no. 5. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. L.G.3441.(No.5). (Box-folder 26/11)
      - Chemin faisant: En valsant, op. 53, no. 6. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. 3441.(No.6). (Box-folder 26/12)
      - Conte de fée, op. 62. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. D. & F.2963, D.S. & Cie.2963. (Box-folder 26/13)
      - Les contes de Perrault, op. 6. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 51 p.; Plate no. D.S. & Cie.2415 (1) through (9).; Contains annotations in pencil, p. 47. (Box-folder 26/14)
      - Contes de la veillée, op. 67. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Piano, four hands; score; 49 p.; Plate no. D.S. & Cie.3038 through 3043. (Box-folder 26/15)
      - Danse fantastique. Paris: A. Choudens, 1896., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.10147. (Box-folder 26/16)
      - Six fables de La Fontaine. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 51 p.; Plate no. H. & Cie.6941 (1), 6943 (2), 6942 (3), 6944 (4), 6945 (5), 6946 (6).; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: French (Box-folder 26/17)
      - Une fête au village. Paris: A. Choudens, 1896., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.C.10157.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 26/18)
      - Impressions de campagne au printemps, op. 123. Paris: A. Choudens, 1892., Solo piano; 108 p.; Plate no. A.C.8311, .8361, .8779, .8780, .8781, .8835, .8836, .8837, .8842, .8844, .8868, .8869, .8870, .8843, .8871, .8881. (Box-folder 26/19)
      - Kermesse, op. 51. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged by G. Pfeiffer for piano, four hands; score; 21 p.; Plate no. L.G.5622. (Box-folder 26/20)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 50, no. 1: Boniment. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. L.G.3565. (Box-folder 26/21)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 50, no. 2: Pan. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 6 p.; Plate no. L.G.3566. (Box-folder 26/22)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 50, no. 3: Marquis et marquise. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. L.G.3567. (Box-folder 26/23)
      - La lanterne magigue, op. 50, no. 4: Trilby. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. L.G.3568. (Box-folder 26/24)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 55, no. 2: Poëte. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. L.G.3440.(2). (Box-folder 27/1)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 55, no. 4: Viennoise. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. L.G.3440.(4).; two copies of p. 7 (Box-folder 27/2)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 55, no. 5: Mignon. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. L.G.3440.(5). (Box-folder 27/3)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 55, no. 6: Bergers et bergères. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 6 p.; Plate no. L.G.3440.(6). (Box-folder 27/4)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 66, no. 4: Lansquenets. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. L.G.3761.(4). (Box-folder 27/5)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 66, no. 5: Esméralda. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. L.G.3762.(5). (Box-folder 27/6)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 66, no. 6: Marcel le Huguenot. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. L.G.3763.(6). (Box-folder 27/7)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 110, no. 2: Vénitienne. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.4512.(No. 2). (Box-folder 27/8)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 110, no. 3: Espagnole. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. L.G.4512.(No. 3). (Box-folder 27/9)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 110, no. 5: Saxonne. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. L.G.4512.(No. 5). (Box-folder 27/10)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 115, no. 1: Norvégienne. Paris: L. Grus, 1892., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.4548.(No. 1). (Box-folder 27/11)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 115, no. 2: Russe. Paris: L. Grus, 1892., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.4548.(No. 2). (Box-folder 27/12)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 115, no. 4: Anglaise. Paris: L. Grus, 1892., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. L.G.4548.(4). (Box-folder 27/13)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 115, no. 5: Orientale. Paris: L. Grus, 1892., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. L.G.4712.(5). (Box-folder 27/14)
      - La lanterne magique, op. 115, no. 6: Styrienne. Paris: L. Grus, 1892., Solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. L.G.4548.(No. 6). (Box-folder 27/15)
      - Menuet-Andante-Gavotte, op. 16. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. D.S. et Cie.1716.(1) through (3). (Box-folder 27/16)
      - Trois morceaux, op. 27. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 13 p.; Plate no. D.S. et Cie. 2151 (1) through (3). (Box-folder 27/17)
      - Novellozza, op. 47. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. D. & F.2962., D.S. & Cie.2962. (Box-folder 27/18)
      - Redowa, op. 141. Paris: H. Tellier, 1893., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. H.T.1101. (Box-folder 27/19)
      - Romance sans paroles, no. 2, op. 120. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. J.3117.H. (Box-folder 27/20)
      - Scènes italiennes, op. 126. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 24 p.; Plate no. D.S.4354 through 4356. (Box-folder 27/21)
      - Scènes poétiques, op. 46, no. 1: Dans les bois. Paris: C. Joubert, n.d., Arranged by G. Pfeiffer for solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. B.et Cie.12562.(1). (Box-folder 27/22)
      - Scènes poétiques, op. 46, no. 2: Dans les champs. Paris: C. Joubert, n.d., Arranged by G. Pfeiffer for solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. B.et Cie.12562.(2). (Box-folder 27/23)
      - Scènes poétiques, op. 46, no. 3: Sur la montagne. Paris: Brandus, n.d., Arranged for piano, four hands; score; 9 p.; Plate no. B.et Cie.12506.(3). (Box-folder 27/24)
      - Scènes poétiques, op. 46, no. 4: Au village. Paris: C. Joubert, n.d., Arranged by G. Pfeiffer for solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. B.et Cie.12562.(4). (Box-folder 27/25)
      - Scherzetto, no. 2, op. 108. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. D.S.4297. (Box-folder 27/26)
      - Sérénade. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. J.4434.H. (Box-folder 27/27)
      - Sérénade à Mabel, op. 138, no. 2. Paris: J. Hamelle, 1892., Solo piano; score; 4 p.; Plate no. J.3527 H. (Box-folder 27/28)
      - Sérénade aux étoiles. Paris: A. Choudens, 1896., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.10143. (Box-folder 27/29)
      - Sonate fantastique, op. 63, no. 2: Les farfadets. Paris: J. Hamelle, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. J.1917.2.H. (Box-folder 27/30)
      - Sonate fantastique, op. 63, no. 3: La fée d'amour. Paris: J. Hamelle, 1897., Solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. J.1918.3.H. (Box-folder 27/31)
      - Suite de danses anciennes et modernes, op. 103, nos. 1-3. Paris: C. Joubert, n.d., Solo piano; score; 14 p.; Plate no. B.et Cie.13155.(1) through (3).; Contents: 1. Minuet 2. Rigodon 3. Gigue (Box-folder 27/32)
      - Suite de danses anciennes et modernes, op. 103, nos. 4-6. Paris: C. Joubert, n.d., Solo piano; score; 28 p.; Plate no. B.et Cie.13155.(4) through (6).; Contents: 4. Mazurk, no. 4 5. Polka, no. 1 6. Valse, no. 8. (Box-folder 27/33)
      - Suite de trois morceaux, op. 116. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Flute and piano; flute part, piano score; 10 p.; 19 p.; Plate no. D.S.4144 (1) through (3). (Box-folder 27/34)
      - Symphonie-Ballet, op. 60, no. 1: Ouverture. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. L.G.3655.(No. 1). (Box-folder 28/1)
      - Symphonie-Ballet, op. 60, no. 2: La cerrito. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.3656.(No. 2). (Box-folder 28/2)
      - Symphonie-Ballet, op. 60, no. 3: Pantomime sentimentale. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. L.G.3657.(No. 3). (Box-folder 28/3)
      - Symphonie-Ballet, op. 60, no. 4: Danse d'almées. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 3658.(No. 4). (Box-folder 28/4)
      - Symphonie-Ballet, op. 60, no. 5: Final-valse. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. 3659.(No. 5). (Box-folder 28/5)
      - Le tasse, op. 39: Danse des bohémiens. Paris: Heugel, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. H.et Cie.9304. (Box-folder 28/6)
      - Le tasse, op. 39: La fête chez le duc d'Este. Paris: G. Hartmann, n.d., Arranged for piano, four hands; score; 17 p.; Plate no. G.1167 H. (Box-folder 28/7)
      - Le tasse, op. 39: Pastorale. Paris: G. Hartmann, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. G.H.1343. (Box-folder 28/8)
      - Trio, no. 2, op. 72: Scherzo. Paris: Durand & Schoenewerk, 1888., Arranged by I. Philipp for solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. D.S.3949. (Box-folder 28/9)
      - Tziganka, op. 134. Paris: J. Hamelle, 1895., Solo piano; score; 14 p.; Plate no. J.3493 H. (Box-folder 28/10)
      - Valse, no. 2, op. 56. Paris: A. Durand, 1910., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. D. & F.2846. (Box-folder 28/11)
      - Valse, no. 3 (Valse-sérénade), op. 71. Paris: A. Durand, n.d., Solo piano; score; 9 p.; Plate no. D.S. & Cie.3105.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil. (Box-folder 28/12)
    - Goossens, Eugène
      - Four conceits, op. 20. London: J. & W. Chester, 1918., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. J. & W.C.2028.1 through .4. (Box-folder 28/13)
      - Epigram, op. 19. London: J. & W. Chester, 1918., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. J. & W.C.3766.; Language note: English; Language note: French (Box-folder 28/14)
      - Kaleidoscope, op. 18. London: J. & W. Chester, 1918., Solo piano; score; 25 p.; Plate no. J. & W.C.2027.1 through .12. (Box-folder 28/15)
      - Deux proses lyriques, op. 16. London: J. & W. Chester, 1917., Voice and piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. J.W.C.3731.; Language note: French (Box-folder 28/16)
      - Two songs, op. 10. London: J. & W. Chester, 1917., Voice and piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. J. & W.C.3733.; Contains annotations in pencil on inside back cover.; Language note: French; Language note: English (Box-folder 28/17)
    - Gounod, Charles François
      - L'Angelus. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Arranged by A. Le Beau for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. A.L.12070. (Box-folder 28/18)
      - Le bal d'enfants. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.L.11791. (Box-folder 28/19)
      - Chanson printanière. Paris: A. Choudens, 1895., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.10081. (Box-folder 28/20)
      - Choral et musette. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.2697. (Box-folder 28/21)
      - Cinq Mars: Ballet Louis XIII. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 15 p.; Plate no. L.G.3455. (Box-folder 28/22)
      - Cinq Mars: Sarabande. Paris: L. Grus, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. L.G.3387. (Box-folder 28/23)
      - La colombe. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 142 p.; Plate no. A.C.758.; Contents: BOX: 28/24 Copy 1: contains sparse annotations in pencil. BOX: 28/25 Copy 2 of the above. BOX: 28/25 Laid in: copyist's manuscripts, 31 p.; 1 p. annotations in the hands of both Diaghilev and Lifar. Printed score also contains extensive emendations and anno-tations in pencil and in ink, in the hands of both Diaghilev and Lifar. BOX: 28/26 Copy 3 of the above. BOX: 29/1 Copy 4 of the above. BOX: 29/2 Copy 5 of the above: incomplete, contains only p. 2 through 18.; Language note: French (Box-folder 28/24-26, Box-folder 29/1-2)
      - Dodelinette. Paris: H. Lemoine, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 7780.HL. (Box-folder 29/3)
      - Filemon e Bauci. [=Philémon et Baucis.] Paris: A. Choudens, n.d. See also: Philémon et Baucis Box 29, Folder 13 See also: Philémon et Baucis Box 30, Folder 1 See also: Philémon et Baucis Shelved item 24, Piano-vocal score; 171 p.; Plate no. A.C.5563.; Language note: Italian (Box-folder 29/4)
      - Gavotte. Paris: A. Choudens, 1895., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.C.9799. (Box-folder 29/5)
      - Impromptu. Paris: H. Lemoine, 1888., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 9510.HL. (Box-folder 29/6)
      - Jeanne d'Arc: Danse bohémienne. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 11 p.; Plate no. 18 (C). (Box-folder 29/7)
      - Marche funèbre d'une marionette. Paris: H. Lemoine, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 7523.HL. (Box-folder 29/8)
      - Matinée de mai. Paris: A. Choudens, 1896., Solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. A.C.10186. (Box-folder 29/9)
      - Le médecin malgré lui. Paris: E. Gallet, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 190 p.; Plate no. 2097.; Laid in: copyist's manuscripts, 90 p. Printed score also contains extensive emendations and annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: French (Box-folder 29/10)
      - Le médecin malgré lui. [Paris]: [A. Choudens], n.d., Piano-vocal score; [18] p.; Plate no. A.C.2097.; incomplete: p. 57-72, 187-190 only; Contains annotations in pencil and in ink.; Language note: French (Box-folder 29/11)
      - Mireille. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 213 p.; Plate no. A.C.1005.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: French (Box-folder S/45)
      - Petite étude-scherzo. Paris: H. Lemoine, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. 9314.HL. (Box-folder 29/12)
      - Philémon et Baucis. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d. See also: Filemon e Bauci, Box 29, Folder 4, Piano-vocal score; 189 p.; Plate no. A.C.703.; Contenst: BOX: 29/13 Copy 1: contains annotations in pencil. BOX: 30/1 Copy 2 of the above. Cover page missing.; Language note: French (Box-folder 29/13, Box-folder 30/1)
      - Philémon et Baucis. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 178 p.; Plate no. A.C.703, 702.; Contains sparse annotations in pencil.; Language note: French (Box-folder S/24)
      - Préludes et fugues pour l'étude préparatoire au Clavecin bien tempéré de Jean Sébastien Bach. Paris: A. Choudens, 1895., Solo piano; score; 52 p.; Plate no. A.C.9800 through 9805. (Box-folder 30/2)
      - Quatuor no. 3. Paris: A. Choudens, 1895. See also: Scherzo, Box 30, Folder 6, Strings; parts for: vn I, vn II, vla, vc (9 p. each).; Plate no. A.C.9809. (Box-folder 30/3)
      - La reine de Saba: Ballet et Marche. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 21 p.; Plate no. A.C. 2743. (Box-folder 30/4)
      - Royal-Menuet. Paris: Le Beau, n.d., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. N.L.342. (Box-folder 30/5)
      - Scherzo. [Quartet, strings, no. 3, A minor: Scherzo.] Paris: A. Choudens, 1895. See also: Quatuor no. 3, Box 30, Folder 3, Arranged by H. Büsser for solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. A.C.10037. (Box-folder 30/6)
      - Sérénade. Paris: A. Leduc, n.d., Arranged for solo piano; score; 2 p.; Plate no. A.L.11926. (Box-folder 30/7)
      - Souvenir d'un bal. Paris: A. Choudens, 1895., Solo piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. A.C.9944. (Box-folder 30/8)
      - Sylvie. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Voice and piano; score; 3 p.; Plate no. A.C.3953.; Language note: French (Box-folder 30/9)
      - Symphony no. 2, E-flat major: 1. Adagio-allegro agitato. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Arranged for piano, four hands; score; 25 p.; Plate no. A.C.1204.(1). (Box-folder 30/10)
      - Symphony no. 2, E-flat major: 2. Larghetto; 3. Scherzo; 4. Final. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Arranged for piano, four hands; score; [41] p.; Plate no. A.C.1204.(2) through (4).; complete in 51 p. pages 26-77 only (Box-folder 30/11)
      - Le tribut de Zamora: excerpts. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 56 p.; Plate no. A.C.5242.; Language note: French (Box-folder 30/12)
      - Ulysse. Paris: A. Choudens, n.d., Piano-vocal score; 112 p.; Plate no. A.C.1299.; Language note: French (Box-folder 30/13)
      - La valse des sylphes. Paris: H. Lemoine, n.d., Solo piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 7794.HL. (Box-folder 30/14)
    - Grainger, Percy Aldridge
      - British folk-music settings: Irish tune from County Derry (no. 6). London: Schott, 1911., Solo piano; score; 7 p. (Box-folder 30/15)
      - British folk-music settings: Shepherd's hey (no. 4). London: Schott, 1911., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; BOX: 30/17 Copy 2 of the above. (Box-folder 30/16-17)
      - British folk-music settings: The Sussex Mummers' Christmas carol (no. 2). London: Schott, 1911., Solo piano; score; 7 p. (Box-folder 30/18)
      - Room music tit-bits: Mock Morris (no. 1). ["Concert version."] London: Schott, 1912., Solo piano; score; 12 p.; Plate no. 3128.; Contains annotations in pencil on verso of title page. (Box-folder 30/19)
      - Room music tit-bits: Mock Morris (no. 1). ["Popular version."] London: Schott, 1912., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. 45.; Published 1912/1913 (Box-folder 30/20)
      - Room-music tit-bits: Walking tune (no. 3). London: Schott, 1912., Solo piano; score; 10 p.; Plate no. 3137.; 2 copies (Box-folder 30/21)
      - Sentimentals: Colonial song (no. 1). London: Schott, 1913., Voice and piano or solo piano; score; 11 p.; Published 1913/1914; no lyrics (Box-folder 30/22)
      - Settings of songs and tunes from William Chappell's Old English popular music: My robin is to the greenwood gone (no. 2). London: Schott, 1912., Solo piano; score; 10 p. (Box-folder 30/23)
    - Grechaninov, Aleksandr Tikhonovich
      - Quatre mélodies, op. 20, no. 4: Le captif. Leipzig: M.P. Belaïeff, 1912., Voice and piano; score; 5 p.; Plate no. 1966 1970.; Language note: Russian; Language note: French; Language note: German (Box-folder 31/1)
    - Grosz, Wilhelm
      - Baby in der Bar, op. 23. Vienna: Universal, 1927., Arranged by the composer for solo piano; score; 43 p.; Plate no. U.E.7523. (Box-folder 31/2)
    - Gurilev, Aleksandr L'vovich
      - Ne shumi ty, rozh', spelym kolosom. Moscow: Gosudarstvennoe izdatel'stvo, Muzykal'nyĭ sektor, 1923., Two voices and piano; score; 7 p.; Plate no. 10065.; Language note: Russian; Language note: German (Box-folder 31/3)
    - Haberbier, E.
      - Valse See: Glinka, Mikhaĭl. Sobranie muzykal'nykh pies, Box 66, Folder 9
    - Hahn, Reynaldo
      - Le bal de Béatrice d'Este. Paris: Heugel, 1911., Arranged by A. Gédalge for piano, four hands; score; 25 p.; Plate no. H. & Cie.24960. (Box-folder 31/4)
      - Ciboulette: selections. Paris: F. Salabert, 1923., Arranged by F. Salabert for solo piano; score; 8 p.; Plate no. E.A.S.2731. (Box-folder 31/5)
    - Haydn, Joseph
      - Symphonie d'enfants. Paris: Costallat, n.d., Condensed score; 5 p.; Plate no. 16906.R.; 2 copies (Box-folder 31/6)
      - Symphonie d'enfants. Paris: [s.n.], n.d., Parts for: vn I, vn II (2 p. each); cb (1 p.); perc (2 copies, 1 p.).; Plate no. R.11759.; 2 copies (Box-folder 31/7)
    - Henderson, Ray See: De Sylva, B. G.
    - Hindemith, Paul
      - Der Dämon, op. 28. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1924., Reduction by H. Uhticke for solo piano; score; 27 p.; Plate no. 31096. (Box-folder 31/8)
      - Hin und zurück, op. 45a. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1927., Piano-vocal score; 23 p.; Plate no. 31960.; Language note: German (Box-folder 31/9)
      - Tanzstücke, op. 19. Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1928., Solo piano; score; 22 p.; Plate no. 32189. (Box-folder 31/10)
    - Holländer, Friedrich